zarca.com 2019-02-20

# Privacy Policy

Zarca Interactive ("Zarca") is an application service provider that provides you, our customer, tools to create and deploy Web surveys, Web forms, Web-based event registration forms, including capabilities to generate reports, upload, input and download data through its unique technology platform for your customers, employees, suppliers and constituents. Like the postal service, we understand that the Information (defined below) we deliver belongs to you and your survey participants, not us. At Zarca, it is a core business principle that we must protect the privacy of our customers and survey participants or we will not have either. With this principle in mind, Zarca created this privacy policy to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy.

You should be assured that our practices stated in this policy are practiced worldwide. Zarca is a global organization, with legal entities, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross borders. We may share information between Zarca entities and transfer it to offices around the world. Some countries may provide less legal protection for personal information than the country in which the information was provided. No matter the country standards, we will still handle the information in the manner we describe here.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected on our web site at the URL [http://www.zarca.com](http://www.zarca.com/)(the "Site") and our Zarca service platform. It does not speak about Zarca practices for Information collected elsewhere or the practices of any third parties, including those of our partners who may display Zarca branding on their sites. The use of Information collected through our service platform shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Customer has engaged Zarca.

If you have questions about this privacy policy please email, [privacy@zarca.com](mailto:privacy@zarca.com)

.

**1\. What Information do we collect?**

Zarca collects information about both you, our customers ("Customers" or "you") and the individuals who participate in, or are invited to participate in, any of your surveys ("Survey Participants"). Collectively, the information collected about you ("Customer Information") and Survey Participants ("Participant Information") are referred to as "Information".

_Customer Information_ : When Customers register on the Site, we ask you to give us your name and contact information: company name, name of contact, title of contact, company address, telephone number, email address, user name and password, and billing information which may include credit card numbers. Customers also provide us with Information regarding the Services you have ordered (e.g., the number of surveys Customers will pay for or whether you want a private or public survey). In addition to the Information you knowingly provide, we also know when and how often you log on to the Site. (See "Tracking Technologies" below.)

_Participant Information_ : We receive Participant Information from both Customers and Survey Participants. You provide us with the email address, and sometimes the name, of each Participant. Before receiving such Information, we contractually require that you warranty that you have a pre-existing relationship with the Survey Participant and/or the Survey Participant's permission to receive electronic messages. Survey Participants provide us with the Information requested by you; for example, their gender or zip code, as well as all answers to the survey questions. Customers are solely responsible for the content of their surveys; we do not control the theme or questions asked in any survey. In order to enhance survey response rates, we record (i) if and when a Survey Participant has responded to a survey and (ii) if and when a Survey Participant has received a reminder. In addition, we receive any Information contained in any communications a Survey Participant makes directly with Zarca. (See "Tracking Technologies" below.)

We also log Customer and Survey Participant Internet Protocol addresses to ensure the accuracy of the survey data and for system administration purposes including tracking a user's session so that we know when, how often and what pages of the Site a user visits. To prevent the need to re-insert user-name and password as you and your Survey Participants move from one page of the Site to the next, we do use a cookie. (See "Tracking Technologies" below).

You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

If you choose to use our referral service on Zarca to share an article from our site, we will ask you for your email address and your referral’s email address. We will automatically send your referral a one-time email in your name inviting him or her to visit the site to review the article. Zarca does not store this information and uses it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

Zarca also receive Information under the direction of its Customers on its service platform and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Zarca's Customer (the data controller). If the Customer requests Zarca to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days. Zarca works with its Customers to help them provide notice to their customers concerning, the purpose for which personal information is collected. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Customers.

**Tracking Technologies Employed on the Site and the Service Platforms**

 _Cookies_  
Like many websites, Zarca uses "cookies" to collect visitor information. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser. They make it possible for us to recognize your browser when you visit and to tell us whether customers and visitors have visited the Site previously. For these purposes your personally identifiable information (such as email address) is tied to personally identifiable information. If you have provided your name or other contact information to Zarca via a web form, we are able to link that information back to the cookie. This information may be used to provide you with information that we believe to be relevant to you based on your actions on our website.

We use persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.

_Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)_  
Our tracking utility company employs clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. These tracking technologies are not tied to our customers' personally identifiable information. The use of tracking technologies by our third party tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each promotional email.

**Widgets**

From time to time our site includes “Widgets”, such as a “Share This”, button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our site; they may also set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the third party company providing the Feature.

**Blogs/Forums**

Our blog on the [www.zarca.com](http://www.zarca.com/) is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

**Testimonials**

From time to time, we post customer testimonials on our website which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. Before posting the testimonial, we obtain the customer's consent to post their name along with their testimonial.

If you want to remove your personal information that is being displayed on our website under public pages please send your request to [privacy@zarca.com](mailto:privacy@zarca.com)

**2\. How Do We Use Information?**

We use your Customer Information in the normal course of our business, for reasons such as contacting you regarding technical support, discuss billing issues, or to bring to your attention any aspect of our mutual business. We may also use your contact information to provide you with policy or product updates or to introduce new products and services. If you do not wish to receive promotional emails from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions included in each promotional email.

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

All Participant Information resides in our database primarily for the benefit of you, our Customers. At your direction, we use a Survey Participant's email address (and perhaps name) to send survey invitations and reminders. We also use Participant Information to improve the performance of our Site and services by analyzing site and user behavior, troubleshooting technical problems, resolving disputes and addressing complaints, and verifying compliance with the Terms of Service.

If Zarca intends to use any Information in a manner that deviates from this Privacy Policy we will provide notice of how we intend to use that Information as we collect it. The use of that specific Information will be used solely as stated in the alternative disclosure.

**Choice**

We collect information for our Customers. If you are a client of one of our Customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Customers that use our service, please contact the Customer that you interact with directly. If you are our Customer and would like to update your account please contact us.

**Data Retention**

Zarca will retain personal data that we process on behalf of our Clients and data we collect from our Clients directly for as long as it is needed to provide services to our Clients. Zarca will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Links to Other Sites**

This site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Zarca. Please be aware that we, Zarca, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

**3\. With Whom Do We  
    Share Information?**

We do not share Information with any third parties except under the following very limited circumstances:

**(a) Participant Information with Customer:** Our business is the provision of tools that allow you, our Customer, to conduct meaningful surveys with your employees, suppliers, customers and constituents. Accordingly, we provide you with access to the Participant Information given in response to the surveys you have conducted. You may use the Participant Information consistent with your own privacy policy and applicable law.

**(b) As You Explicitly Allow:** We may share or otherwise use your Customer Information as you explicitly allow us and we may share Participant Information as both you and the Survey Participant expressly allow. For example, you are given the opportunity to either hide or make available to Survey Participants certain Customer contact information in connection with any survey.

**(c) Agents Acting on Our Behalf:** We may share some of your Information with other companies who provide us with technical and other type of services such as a credit card processor. They will be contractually granted access to only that Information which is necessary for them to do their jobs and they will be prohibited from using the Information for any other purpose including marketing or sharing the Information with any other party. We do not share any personally identifiable information with third parties who are not services providers.

**(d) For Legal Reasons:** We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may also share your Information to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our terms of use, or as otherwise required by law. Please note that under the Privacy Shield Framework, Zarca and is Customers may be subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, or any other U.S. authorized statutory body, relating to the use and disclosure of Information.

**(e) Affiliates and Acquisition:** We may share Information with our affiliated companies or during any real or potential acquisition or merger of our company by or with another. We will notify you if your Information becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

**4\. Can the Information  
    be Changed?**

Your Customer Information may be viewed and modified in our active database in real-time at any time. If you wish to request deletion of data from our site, please contact us at [privacy@zarca.com](mailto:privacy@zarca.com). The changed Information may remain in archives and records for some period of time. Once a Survey Participant has submitted a survey, the Survey Participant will not be able to access his Information through the Site. Survey Participants may contact you and you, in turn, will be able to view the Survey Participant's collected Information and, where appropriate, work with us in modifying such Information. If the client requests Zarca to remove the Survey Participant's data or the Client's data, Zarca will respond to their Client's request within 30 business days. 

**5\. How Is Information Protected?**

Our Site has substantial and elaborate security measures in place to protect your Information. Unique user names and passwords must be entered each time a person logs on. The Site is hosted in a secure server environment that uses a firewall and other technology to reasonably prevent access from outside intruders. Internally, we use security-logs, train our employees and limit access to essential personnel only. When transmitting sensitive Information, we use encryption technology. All our technology and processes are not, however, guarantees of security. Please keep your user name and password secret and let us know at [privacy@zarca.com](mailto:privacy@zarca.com)

if you learn or suspect that our security has been breached. 

**6\. Changes in the Privacy Policy:**

As we are constantly improving our services and expanding our business, we retain the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. In the event we make such changes, we will announce the changes and post the new policy on the Site. Information collected after the new policy is posted will be used in conformance with the new policy. Information gathered under the old policy will continue to be used in conformance with that policy unless we, in conjunction with the Customer, notify Survey Participants of the changes and the Survey Participant does not prohibit the use of the Information in conformance with the new policy. If we make any material changes we will notify you or our Client by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield and Data Dispute Resolution**

Zarca complies with the U.S.-E.U. Privacy Shield Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Zarca has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Framework principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, and to view Zarca's certification, please visit [ https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework ](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework) and [ https://www.privacyshield.gov/list ](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

**Independent Recourse Mechanism for EU and Swiss Privacy Shield Complaints.**

For purposes of our Customers that require compliance with the U.S.-E.U. or U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield Framework, Zarca undertakes the following alternative dispute resolution process relating to privacy complaints and final resolutions: the independent dispute resolution body designated to address complaints and provide appropriate recourse, free of charge, to the individual, shall be through an arbitration panel, in accordance with the EU data protection authorities (“DPAs”), and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (“FDPIC”), with all privacy, including human resource (“HR”) and non-HR related complaints being addressed by said mechanism.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Zarca Interactive Inc., commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact at [privacy@zarca.com](mailto:privacy@zarca.com)and include the statement “Privacy Complaint” in the subject line of your email. Or you may contact us via mail, at:

2291 Wood Oak Drive  
Suite 300  
Herndon, VA 20171

Zarca Interactive Inc., has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland, in the context of the employment relationship.

In order to invoke arbitration under the Framework, the aggrieved party must: (1) first, raise the claimed violation directly with Zarca and afford the Zarca an opportunity to resolve the issue within the timeframe set forth in Section III.11(d)(i) of the Privacy Shield’s Principles; (2) then, make use of the independent recourse mechanism under the Principles, which is at no cost to the individual; and to the extent unresolved; (3) raise the issue through their Data Protection Authority to the Department of Commerce and afford the Department of Commerce an opportunity to use best efforts to resolve the issue within the timeframes set forth in the Letter from the International Trade Administration of the Department of Commerce, at no cost to the individual.

Zarca commits to cooperate with DPAs and the FDPIC, and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship.

Zarca complies with the possibility that, under certain limited conditions, individuals may invoke binding arbitration. As a reminder, we may be required to share personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Zarca recognizes that in certain circumstances, Zarca may be held liable in cases of onward transfers of personal information to third parties.

**Additional Information**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or the Site, you may contact us at [privacy@zarca.com](mailto:privacy@zarca.com)

2291 Wood Oak Drive  
Suite 300  
Herndon, VA 20171

Last Updated: 11/5/2018
